Hello and welcome back. Let us now introduce a different concept into
【未完成版本】大家好 欢迎回来 让我们来看看图像恢复的另一个概念
imaging painting. Basically, we're going to do a Smart Cut
我们这一节要学习的是智能剪切与粘贴
and Paste. We're going to first introduce the
我们首先介绍这个概念
concept and then see how we obtain excellent results by merging that with
然后再来看看如何将其与之前视频中讲过的
the type of variation and formulations that we just talked about in the previous
变分法和公式法结合起来得到很好的结果
videos. So, why do we need an another type of
那么 我们为什么需要另一种形式的图像修复技术呢？
impainting? There's a number of reasons.
其实有很多原因
But one of them is in the example that we showed in the previous video.
其中一个原因 在之前视频里的例子中就有体现
We discussed the fact that. PDEs and variational formulations are
我们知道 实际上偏微分方程和变分公式
excellent tools for impainting smooth regions.
用于光滑连续区域的修复是非常好的
They're not as good for impainting texture as we see here.
但是我们这里可以看到 它们在纹理的修复上就不是很理想了
That we need to basically extend this nice texture inside the region to be
我们需要将这些区域中的纹理扩展到损坏了的区域上去
impainted. And that's where this other type of
在这种情形下 这种类型的技术
techniques become extremely powerful. Let me blow this region so we can explain
就非常有用了 我们把这个区域放大了看看
what's going on. We need now to inpaint inside here and we
便于我们解释这个技术 我们现在需要修复这里面的区域
see that there are plotters that we want to extend.
这里的这些图案是我们想要扩展上去的
We could actually write partial differential equations that extend that
当然这里用偏微分方程来扩展这个流到这些区域也是可行的
flow towards this region. But it would be much harder to write a
但是对于这里的这种有多个方向的纹理
partial differential equation that extends this type of texture that goes in
用偏微分方程的方法 就比较困难了
multiple directions. But we have another technique.
但是我们还有另一种技术
Remember we talk about non-local means for image denoising.
回忆一下我们讲过的非局部均值方法处理图像噪声
We happen to exploit the same type of approach but for image impainting.
我们恰好可以利用同种类型的方法 不过这一次是用在图像修复上
Here is the basic idea. Let us assume that we take a a patch
我们来看看其基本思想 假设从这里取一小片图像出来
here. This patch is very particular.
这个小片比较特别
It contains some known information and some unknown information.
它包含了一些已知信息区域和未知信息区域
Now in the same way as the non-local means, I can go around and looking for
现在使用跟非局部平均一样的办法
similar patches but, in this case, I do the comparison only in the region of
我们在周围寻找相似的小片 但是我们只对已知信息的区域做对比
known pixels. So, for example, I basically take a patch
例如 我们在这里取相同大小的一片
of the same size as here but I only look at this region.
但是我们只关注这个区域
And I say is this region similar to this region and I keep going around, for
并且这部分区域跟这部分区域相似 然后继续
example I might take a byte here. And once again I look only at this
比如我们可能查看这里 然后我们还是只关注这部分区域
region. So, at least they translate the known
这样就至少把已知区域平移到了那个区域上
region towards dark patch and I keep going and I find one or more patches dark
我们继续这个过程 最终我们在已知的区域里可能发现
in the known region, they're basically equal or very similar.
一个或多个这样的小片 它们相同或者非常相似
Let us assume that I find one, for example I find it here.
假设我们已经找到了一个 比如在这里找到一个
And we draw the region and we say okay, this is very similar to this here.
我把这里涂一下 然后我们就说 好吧 这跟这里非常相似
So how can I fill this region? I basically copy this.
那么我们如何填充这个区域呢？只要把这部分复制过来就可以了
The unknown becomes the known part of the matching part.
未知的区域就变成了匹配部分的已知部分
I can copy the whole region. I can copy only a few border pixels and I
可以复制整个区域 也可以只复制一些边界像素
can copy only from one part or I can find a number of patches that are similar and
还可以只从一个部分复制 或者 如果我们找到了多个小片
copy their average or any other type of function.
跟这部分像素相似 那也可以取它们的平均 或者应用其他任何形式的函数 然后复制到这里
But the concept is the same concept as in all local means.
不过其基本概念跟非局部平均的基本思想是一致的
Find similar patches but now similarity's based only on the known region.
找到相似的小片 但是现在相似只基于已知的区域
Once you find similar patches. Copy the unknown region towards here.
一旦我们找到了相似的区域 就可以复制已知区域到这里
When we do that, we finish and we know here.
只要做了这个 这部分就完成了 并且它变成了已知的
And we can keep propagating. This now becomes known because I just
这样我们就可以继续传递下去 这部分现在变成了已知的
filled that in. And then we can keep going inside and
【未完成版本】因为它已经被填充了 然后就可以继续
keep going inside and keep going inside. So a basic idea is that we look at every
不断地重复这个过程 所以其基本思想就是检查所有未知的像素
unknown pixel. We start from pixels that have a lot of
我们从周围有很多已知区域的像素开始
known area surrounding it. We fill them.
不断填充它们
And then we keep going with the other and the other pixels, until we finish
然后对其他像素不断重复这个过程 直到填满所有的像素
basically filling in everything. And let me go back to the previous slide.
我们回到前一张幻灯片
And we basically see. That we feel nicely the texture, we also
我们可以看到 这些纹理看起来要好很多
feel nicely the texture here. And we actually have feel the texture in
这里这些纹理也不错 实际上
a very nice fashion all around. Just by the same concept as the non-local
整个图像上的纹理都得到了很好的修复 就是用了跟非局部平均相同的概念
means. Now, that, we can actually combine with
现在我们可以将其与变分公式结合起来
variational formulations. What I just told you, we can write in a
我们刚才谈过 可以写出其变分公式
variational formulation, but we can keep adding additional constraints.
不过我们还要加上一些额外的限制
For example, we could say okay, if this patch found a friend here, meaning a
比如 我们可以说 好吧 如果这个小片在这里找到了一个朋友
patch that is very similar to it, I want to make sure that the patch next to it,
也就是说一个跟它很相似的小片 我想确保跟它相邻的小片
let me just use a different pen. I want to make sure.
不好意思 我换一下笔的颜色 我想要确保
That the bunch next to it finds a similar part next to the previous one.
跟它相邻的这个小片 找到一个与前一个相邻的相似部分
So that would help me. In this search it will make it faster but
那这个就可以帮助我们 这会加快搜索的过程
it will also force that this region is smoothly copied here and that can be
并且还会强制这个区域平滑地复制到这里
posed in a variational formulation by for example by asking.
这样就能通过例如寻找平移向量来得出变分公式
That the translation vectors. So this part got translated from here.
这部分从这里平移到这里
This part got translated from here. We have two translation vectors.
这部分平移到这里 我们有了两个平移向量
We can force the translation vectors to change smoothly.
我们可以强制平移向量平滑变化
And that's, it's a variation in formulation, for example, we can take the
这就得到了变分公式 例如
derivatives of the coordinates of the translation vectors and penalize when
我们可以对平移向量求对坐标方向的导数
those derivatives are too high. That means that basically, you're jumping
如果导数太大就进行相应的惩罚
all around to get those. New patches.
我们就只在周围得到一些新的小片
All these concepts can be incorporated into one variation or formulation, can
所有这些概念可以组合成一个变分公式
become very rich. We can incorporate the PDEs type, or the
这样就相当富集了 我们可以合并偏微分方程
variation and formulation type of smooth continuation that we saw in the previous
或者光滑连续变分公式 如前所见
videos. We can incorporate this Smart Cut and
我们可以合并智能剪切和粘贴到
Paste all in one large variation and formulation.
一个大的变分公式里
And then you obtain very nice results as we see here, we basically have an object
就可以得到一个如这里这个一样好的结果
that has been removed, as we see here, by this combination of variational
我们可以看到 这里有个物体被移除了 这是通过组合
formulations with Smart Cut and Paste. Here is another example and we are going
变分公式和智能剪切粘贴得到的 这里是另一个例子
to see this example again in the next video is going to exp, as I'm going to
很快我还会在下一个视频中继续讲解这个例子
explain soon. Again here, remember this image looks
经过修复过的这张图片看起来非常好
perfect that's because impainting, but we basically have removed this lamp from
我们把这个灯移除掉
this image and got a very, very nice result.
得到了一个非常好的结果
Here is yet another example where we basically remove the bars.
这里这个例子 是移除了这些栅栏
And we get a nice result by this combination of Cut and Paste in a
我们通过组合剪切粘贴和变分公式 得到了一个很好的结果
variational formulation. By now we have basically seen two type
我们已经见过两种
of, or three type of concepts. PDEs and variational formulations, that's
或者三种概念 偏微分方程和变分公式
almost one group because the standard variation of formulation leads to PDEs.
这两个基本上是算同一种 因为标准变分公式得到的也是偏微分方程
And then we saw this Smart Cut and Paste. And we saw how we can combine them all
然后是智能剪切与粘贴 我们也见过了如何将他们组合在一起
together to get very, very nice image and painting results.
然后得到很好的图像修复结果
Before I show you some video impainting concepts, I want to demo in painting in
在我介绍视频修复的概念之前 我想演示一下
real time. And I'm going to do that in the next
实时修复 我们将在下一个视频里讲解这个
video. Looking forward to seeing you again then.
希望能再次见到大家
Thank you.
谢谢大家